Guide to the Robert Nelson Bush Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert Nelson Bush papers
1936-1988
SC0476
Bush, Robert Nelson.
13 Linear feet 30 boxes
The bulk of Bush's papers pertain to his years at Stanford, 1945-1988; earlier materials include his student work and several files pertaining to his tenure as Dean of the Faculty at Kansas State Teachers College. Included in his Stanford papers are his subject files which contain notes, articles by Bush and others, reprints, newsletters, clippings, and other items; manuscript, typescript, and published versions of his writings and speeches; class materials; audio tapes; and one film. His research interests centered on secondary and higher education and teacher training; there is also material from research projects conducted in Australia.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Robert N. Bush, 1994, and transfer from Cubberley Library, 2002.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Robert N. Bush was Professor of Education at Stanford University from 1945 until his retirement in 1976, when he was appointed Professor Emeritus. He cofounded the Stanford Center for Research and Development in Teaching and served as its director from 1965 to 1976. He was instrumental in the development of two educational innovations: microteaching and the flexible schedule.
Description of the Collection
The bulk of Bush's papers pertain to his years at Stanford, 1945-1988; earlier materials include his student work and several files pertaining to his tenure as Dean of the Faculty at Kansas State Teachers College. Included in his Stanford papers are his subject files which contain notes, articles by Bush and others, reprints, newsletters, clippings, and other items; manuscript, typescript, and published versions of his writings and speeches; class materials; audio tapes; and one film. His research interests centered on secondary and higher education and teacher training; there is also material from research projects conducted in Australia.
Access Terms
Bush, Robert Nelson.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Faculty.; Education, Secondary--Australia.; Education, Secondary--Curricula.; Education, Secondary--United States.; Education.; Teacher-student relationships.; Teachers--Training of.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 23 box(es)
  - Bush's subject files
    - The Needs Concept in Curriculum Development Oct. 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Criticism of Secondary Education (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Teacher Education (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Teacher Education (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Supervision (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Costs of Attending Secondary Schools (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Junior High School (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gifted-Talented Pupils (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Counseling (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Student Needs (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Curriculum-Secondary School (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Curriculum-Secondary School (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Curriculum-Secondary School (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Curriculum Core (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Special Curriculum Guidance (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Special Curriculum Guidance (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General Curriculum Art (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Curriculum Music (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Curriculum Mathematics (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Curriculum Foreign Languages (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - General Curriculum Foreign Languages (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - General Curriculum Social Studies (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Curriculum Social Studies (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - General Curriculum Social Studies (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - General Curriculum Health, P.E. & Recreation (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - General Curriculum English (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Curriculum Business (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - General Curriculum Home Economics (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - General Curriculum Industrial Arts/ Trade and Industry (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - General Curriculum Work Experience/ Vocational Education (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - General Curriculum Science (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General Curriculum Science (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Secondary Education Special Curriculum Vocational Guidance (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Secondary Education Seminar in Secondary Education (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Secondary Education General (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Secondary Education In-Service Education (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Secondary Education European Middle-Near Eastern (Comparative) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Secondary Education Special Curriculum Latin Grammar School (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Secondary Education Special Curriculum Academy (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Secondary Education Special Curriculum Development of 19th century High School (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Secondary Education Special Curriculum American High School 1900-1950 Historical Development Amer. High School 1950- Historical Development (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Secondary Education Special Curriculum Organization (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Secondary Education Certification (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Secondary Education Accreditation (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Secondary Education Comparative Australian Secondary Education Comparative (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Life Adjustment Education (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Life Adjustment Education (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Life Adjustment Education (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Life Adjustment Education (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Administration-General Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Secondary Administration (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Secondary Administrator (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Secondary Pupils (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Pupil & Adolescence (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Administration Of Educational Program--Curriculum (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scheduling (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Academic Procedures--Grading and Marking System (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Extra-Curricular (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Staff (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Salaries (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Articulation-- related with College, College Entrance Requirements (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Building and Plant (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Financing (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Public Relations (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Brochures and Essays (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Brochures and Essays (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Notes (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Speech to Sydney Australia Rotary Club May 2, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Tunisian Education Field Notes Taken by R. Bush April, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Western Civilization (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Politics (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Speeches Made (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Higher Education (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Higher Education (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Higher Education (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Ed. Soc. Sociology (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Ed. Soc. Sociology (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Occupational Information & Trends (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Occupational Information & Trends (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Occupational Information & Trends (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Family Life (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - American Civilization (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - American Civilization (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - American Civilization (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - American Civilization (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - American Civilization (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - American Civilization (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Federal-State Aid to Education (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Instruction (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Junior College (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Teaching Competence/ Efficiency Qualities of Successful Teacher-Selective Admissions (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Teacher-Pupil Relationship (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Teacher-Pupil Relationship (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Teacher-Pupil Relationship (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Educational Novels (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Human Relations (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Human Relations (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Teacher Education (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Case Method/ Research Design (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Personnel Notes (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Administration-Teacher Relations (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Teacher Morale (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Teacher Selection (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Teacher Placement (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Teacher Induction (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Economic Welfare/ Salaries & Cost of Living (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Economic Welfare/ Home Ownership (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Economic Welfare/ Dependents (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Health-General (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Work Load (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Tenure (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Teacher Supply and Demand (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Code of Ethics (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Adjustment to Community (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Teachers' Organizations (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Merit Rating (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Motivation-Purpose, Incentive (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Mental Health (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Teacher Evaluation (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Evaluation-General (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Evaluation-General (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Educational Psychology (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Educational Psychology (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Adolescent Psychology (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Counselor Role (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Learning (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Measurement-General (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Evaluation-Critical Thinking (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Evaluation-Attitudes (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Evaluation-Test Norms (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Evaluation-Measuring Teacher Ability (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - History of Philosophy of Education (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - International Education (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Teacher Assignment (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Financial Trends in Education (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Administration (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Health Education (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Peer Education (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Competency Based Teacher Education (CBTE) (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Performance Based Teacher Education (PBTE) (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Research Design/ Case Studies (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Teacher Supply and Demand (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Comparative Education- Russia (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Comparative Education India (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Comparative Education Great Britain (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Comparative Education-French (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Comparative Education-China (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Comparative Education-Norway (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Why Students choose to teach (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Educational Methods (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Educational Psychology (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Evaluation-General (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Federal Policy toward Education (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Nominal Group Method (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Parental Involvement in Education (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - National Assessment (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Tenure (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Testing--Basic Skills, Gallup (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Numbers as a form of ID (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Education/Leadership (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Teacher Role in Research (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Compensatory Education (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Innovations in Education--use of Multimedia (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Innovations in Education--General (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Teacher Aides--Lay Teachers (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Teacher Education--General (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Teacher of Tomorrow (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Stanford School of Education (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Inner-City Schools (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Special Education (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Cultural Education (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Assorted Bibliographical References (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Journal of Experimental Education (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Experimental Teacher Training (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Gifted-Talented Pupils (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Drop-Outs (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - National Standard (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Grouping Programs (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Fed Govt. Elementary/Secondary Education Act of 1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Accreditation: NCATE National Council for the Accreditation of Teacher Education (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Teacher Education--Foreign (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Flexible Schedule--Experimental (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Student Demonstration against Administration (UC Berkeley) (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Study Abroad (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Guidance (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Curriculum-General (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Curriculum-General (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Curriculum-Humanities (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Curriculum-Mathematics (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Curriculum-Foreign Languages (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Curriculum-Art (Aesthetic Education) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Curriculum-English (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Curriculum-Vocational Education (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Curriculum-Greek (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Curriculum-Physical Education (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Curriculum-Economics (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Curriculum-Science (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Curriculum-Social Studies (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Secondary Education Criticism (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Selective Education (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Foreign Impressions of American Education (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - (Recent) circa 1959 Trends in Education (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - High School Characteristic Inventory (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - High School/College Related (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Sayings/ Quotes (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Teacher Salaries (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Compulsory education (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Learning (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Learning (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - World Affairs--General (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Bussing (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Future of Education (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Unclassified (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 1,2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 3 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 4,5,6,7 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 8,9 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 8 [revised] (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 10 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 11 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 12 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 13 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 13 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 14 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Bulletin(s): 15 & Objectives of Program, Participants, Staff, and Reports on School Programs (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - The Newsletter: Stanford Social Education Investigation, Volume I: 1-9 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Materials from a report to the Ford Foundation, 1970
    - Ford Foundation Project Narrative Final Report [draft] Summer 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation Project Narrative Final Report [draft w/ editing] (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix I: Original Proposal (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix II: Enrollment in the Program (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix III: Support from School Districts (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix IV: The Appraisal Guide Studies (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix IV: The Appraisal Guide Studies (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix V: Microteaching and Video taping (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix V: Microteaching and Video taping (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix VI: School Experimentation and Flexible Scheduling (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix VI: School Experimentation and Flexible Scheduling (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix VII: Application; Appendix VIII: Stanford Center for Research and Development in Teaching (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix VIII: Stanford Center for Research and Development in Teaching (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Ford Foundation Report Appendix IX: Brochures Describing Program; Appendix X: Book "Breaking through in Teacher Ed: [missing] (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Extra Material, Ford Foundation Report July 1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Extra Material, Ford Foundation Report July 1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Extra Material, Ford Foundation Report July 1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Extra Material, Ford Foundation Report July 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between R. Bush + Mrs. Roberta Lynch; March 1966-July 1970 Re: Ford Foundation Project Final Report (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Reports, articles, speeches, and other miscellaneous items, primarily by Bush
    - Stanford Micro Teaching Operations: Summer 1965 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Stanford University School of Teaching; Micro-Teaching: A Description; Summer 1966 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Ford Foundation Final Report (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Financial Statements; Sept. 1, 1963-Aug. 31,1964 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Award (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Westinghouse ASD Group @ Stanford Brochure (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - The Pyramid System Brochure (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - ASCI Alta California Systems INC. Brochure (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Publications of the Faculty (March 1936-1970) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Article on Center for Research & Development in Teaching (Stanford, CA) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Instruction in Citizenship in California High Schools (December, 1941) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Photographs (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Report: Teacher Education--An Urgent Matter (October, 1966) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Documentation of Retirement of RN Bush 2/76-9/76 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Teaching in Small Groups ( A Working Outline) July 20, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Publications of the Faculty (Sept. 1, 1958-August 31, 1959) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Topical Outline of Field of Secondary Education RN Bush (July 1967) (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Stanford University Education 214: "Curriculum and Instruction in the Social Studies" (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Clippings: Urban/Rural Leadership Training vs. Retirement 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Draft of Letter to Ruth Re: Personal Subjects (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Press Clippings (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Press Clippings (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Introduction for Walter Myer (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Workshops: 1941, Summer 1942 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Kansas State Teacher's College of Emporia Bulletin Information 1943-44, 1944-45 [edited] (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Report to the Stanford University Senate, 1/8/81 by J. Myron Atkin, Dean (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Janis Ahmadjian-Baer's Doctoral Thesis August 1980 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Format for the Clinical Approach to the Training of Teachers (Summer 1963) (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Stanford Social Education Investigation Summer 1940, Unit on Govt. (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Report: On Visit to the New England Program in Teacher Ed, Durham, N.H. October 12-15, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Report: On Visit to New England Program in Teacher Education October 16-21, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Presentation: Research, Development, and Innovation in Teacher Education (February 17, 1966) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Outline of Speech for: Chief State School Officers Conference (July 30, 1970) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Talk given before G.S.O. by RN Bush (April 11, 1973) (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Review of Doctoral Programs in Education: Louisiana State U, McNeese State U, Northeast Louisiana U, Northwestern State U, U of New Orleans, (August 31, 1976) (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Seminar: Major Problems and Issues in Secondary Education (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Outline of Speech for Jesuit Educational Conference (August 3, 1964) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Presentation: Micro-Teaching/ Controlled Practice in the Training of Teachers (April 30, 1964)[Rough Draft and Final Copy] (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Comment :State and Institutional Responsibility For Teacher Ed. and Certification Nov. 20,1963 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "To the Parents of the Elementary School Children" Friday, Dec. 10, 1943? (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Outline and Speech, "Remarks to Faculty Meeting, Kansas State Teacher's College of Emporia" October, 11, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - First Attempt at Summary Curriculum Committee April 1, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Kansas State Teacher's College "Providing Curriculum and Instruction to Students" April, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "Secondary Education's Goal: A Democratic Citizen" Nov. 4, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Proposal to Establish A Consultant Service for Educational Personnel" 1/43 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "The State of Youth" March-April, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Speech: "Teaching History in the War and Post-War World"10/6/43 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Preface to "A Study of Shared Governance of Teacher Ed" RN Bush 1978 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Teacher Corps Evaluation, 1978 Teacher Corps U of Nebraska at Omaha (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - "The Newest Model in Town: Teacher Corps 1978 and Beyond" Las Vegas, Nevada (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Draft Notes on the Professional Decision Side of the Teacher Behavior Spectrum (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - New Devices and New Techniques in Teacher Education (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - The Future of Laboratory Schools at Ill. State Normal University (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - A Redefinition of the Role of the Teacher: The Teacher and Interpersonal Relationships (Emporia, Kansas) (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - MEMORANDUM on Secondary Education, Sacramento School District (August, 1968) [Rough Draft] (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Secondary Education Programs Scottsdale, Arizona MEMORANDUM (December 19,1968) (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "The Important (sic) Is to Teach The Pupil How to Think" Interviewed(sic): R. Bush, Translator from the Portuguese: M. Costa (unedited translation) (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Secondary Education Study (October, 1961) (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "Irrigation Law in Colorado" Final Thesis June, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - CTA Journal Oct. 1960 p. 6 "The High School of the Future" (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Sears-95th Anniversary luncheon; Speech Preparation (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Encyclopedia of Education, draft of "Teacher Assignments" April 22, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Teaching: The Largest Profession"; April 1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Journal of California Teachers Association; October 1962 "We Must Prepare the Best" RN Bush, page 16 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Can We Develop Curriculum-Proof Teachers?" 1/20/68, final, 2 drafts (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Today, Autumn 1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Computer Scheduling: Resources and Design, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Making the School Schedule by Computer: Opening New Educational Alternatives" 1968 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Seminar: "Teaching and Administrative Roles", April 1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Address: "New Directions for Research and Development in Teacher Education" @ University of Texas, Austin 5/3/67 edited, unedited copies (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Address: "The National Goals and Secondary Schools" @ Cubberly Conference July 27, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Washington Education March 1961 "The Teaching Act" p 10 R. Bush (Box 17, Folder 12)